Autograph Book; Collection ua933
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Autograph Book Collection
1857-1890
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua933
0.75 cubic ft.
Collection is made up of autograph books from the New York State Normal School.
Historical Note
Autograph books, a precursor to the modern yearbook, were utilized by many college and university students to collect notes of remembrance from fellow classmates. The New York State Normal School was no exception. The students would collect autographs from friends and classmates, leaving heartfelt notes and poems to each other. Often accompanied by these notes were small photographs of each person, or even small gifts left within the pages of the book. This practice was seemingly common at the school, until the introduction of institutional yearbooks published by the college itself around the turn of the century.
Scope and Contents
The content of this collection is made up of twelve autograph books from the New York State Normal School dating from 1857-1890. Each book is made up of autographs from students at the school, often accompanied by photographs, small tokens of friendship, and heartfelt notes.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Autograph albums; Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Teachers -- Training of; UAlbany Student Groups
- Lizzie Smith Autograph Book, "Boquet Album", 1854-1855 (Item 1)
  Biographical / Historical
  Elizabeth Shriner Smith was born 19 August 1834, daughter of Susan Becker and Cyrus Smith, in Enfield, Tompkins County, New York. She was educated, first in common school, afterward at Ithaca Academy, and finally graduated from Albany Normal School with her twin brother, William, in 1855. She taught school several terms in the Ithaca public schools. She was married December 7, 1858 to Lyman Ostrom and they lived in Nassau, Rensselaer County, New York. They had two children-Mary, who died in 1860 in infancy, and William Lyman, born 16 June 1862.
  Lyman Ostrom was born 15 January 1834 and was killed in Chain Bridge, VA., outside of Petersburg, VA on 10 May 1864 while serving in a New York Regiment. He had enlisted in the army in August of 1862 and served in Washington, DC, Folley Island, Florida, and was killed in a battle at Chester Station, VA while tearing up the railroad between Petersburg and Richmond.
- The Tablet of Friendship, 1856 January 31-1857 July 09 (Box 1 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 1)
- Autographs, 1860 July 12 (Box 1 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 2)
- Autographs, 1860 July 12 (Box 1 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 3)
- Autographs, 1860 July 12 (Box 1 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 4)
- Autographs, 1861 January 31 (Box 1 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 5)
- Autographs, 1861 January 31 (Box 1 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 6)
- Autographs, 1862 June 23-1886 August 5 (Box 2 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 1)
- Autographs, 1868 January 29 (Box 2 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 2)
- Autographs, 1874 June 26-1875 July 7 (Box 2 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 3)
- Autographs, 1884-1886 (Box 2 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 4)
- Autographs, 1888 (Box 2 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 5)
- Autographs, 1889 (Box 2 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 6)
- Autographs, 1890 (Box 2 (Autograph Book Collection), Folder 7)